Start entry sequence.
Initializing LCL ionization.
Plug depth stable at default value.
Autonomous systems are go.
Boot-up voltage has cleared the threshold.
Launch prerequisites achieved.
Synchronization rate requirements are go.
Pilot.
Please specify linguistic norm for cognitive functions.
Umm, it's my first time, so... Japanese.
Roger.
So, the new plug suit wasn't provided on time.
This suit is tight around my chest, I don't like it.
Sorry about sending you into combat in the provisional unit on such short notice.
I finally get to pilot, so it's fine.
It's because you're a troublemaker.
Well, it's in your hands now.
It's moving, it's moving!
This is great... I'm so excited!
Alright.  Provisional Evangelion Unit 05.
Activate!
Defend the limbo area at all costs!
We cannot allow it to escape from Acheron.
How could a containment system as secure as Cocytus be neutralized?
It was within the realm of possibility.
On its own, humanity is incapable of holding the Angels in check.
The analysis pulling a permafrost extraction
of the Third Angel was so extensive,
all that what was left were the bones.
And that was the conclusion.
With that said, good luck!
Happiness doesn't walk to you~
That's why I walk to it~
One step a day, making three steps in three days~
Three steps forward, and two steps back~
Life is a one-two punch!
Ooh, here it comes!
Activate A.T. field!
Target inbound.
EVA Unit 05 is about to engage the hostile.
It's hard to move in this thing!
I guess I'll have to use brute force!
Upper outer wall integrity compromised!
The final seal is about to be breached!
Target has broken through limbo area.
Now moving into Acheron.
Get Unit 05 to do something!
Don't you run away!
Ow, it hurts!
It really hurts...
But it's fun, so whatever!
I'm out of time!
This unit won't hold, either!
These spare limbs were forcefully synchronized, they don't have enough power!
Fine!
I'll let you have an arm!
Just...
... die already!
Target obliterated.
Unit 05 has been vaporized.
Pilot appears to have been ejected.
So, Unit 05's self-destruct program was successfully activated.
Though, I'm not so sure about involving a kid in the affairs of adults.
Ow ow ow...
They didn't say synchronizing with an EVA would be this intense...
Well, at least I'm alive.
I'm not so sure about involving
an adult to achieve my own goals.
Farewell, EVA Unit 05.
You did good.
Evangelion New Theatrical Version: Break
It's been three years since the two of us last came here.
I ran away that day, and never came back here since.
I have no recollection at all that Mom was buried here.
I don't even remember her face.
People live on by forgetting their memories.
But, there are memories that should never be forgotten.
Yui taught me that invaluable lesson.
I come here to remind myself of it.
Aren't there any pictures of her?
There aren't any left.
This graveyard is just for appearances.
There is no body.
You threw everything away, just like my teacher said.
It's all inside my heart.
That will do for now.
It's time.  I'll head back first.
Father!
Umm...
I'm glad that I was able to talk to you today.
I see.
Well, Shinji?
You were worried about all sorts of things,
but they weren't so bad once you met him, right?
Aren't you glad that you came instead of sulking at home?
It's the anniversary of your mother's death, after all.
It's only because you forced me to, Misato-san.
That's because deep down inside you, Shinji-kun, you wanted to go.
Be more honest with yourself.
Being honest only results in painful thoughts.
You lived up to everyone's expectations and saved us.
Have more confidence in yourself.
I'm sure your father was proud of you.
This is Katsuragi.
What did you say?!
The Seventh Angel has been detected off the coast of Sakami Bay.
The 2nd fleet is currently engaging the enemy.
A state of emergency was declared 3 minutes ago.
I also have visual confirmation here.
I am currently transporting the pilot of Unit 01.
Activate Task 03 on Unit 00 immediately!
Can't do that, Task 02 is already in progress.
Task 02?
No way!
It is Unit 02!
Wow, she took out the core in one shot!
No, that's a decoy!
Take this!
Situation resolved!
The blocking-off of all designated areas is complete.
Currently, EVA Unit 02 is being
transported via Route 1 from Sagami.
It will arrive at the 4th Depot on time.
Wow, so Unit 02 is red?
It's not just the coloring that makes it different!
After all, Unit 00 is just a prototype and Unit 01 is only a test type.
But, Unit 02 is different.
Designed specifically for combat, it's the world's first genuine Evangelion!
The official type!
Introducing the ace of the European Air Force, Captain Shikinami Asuka Langley.
She's the Second Child, and the pilot of EVA Unit 02.
It's been a while, Misato!
So she's the Commander's pet who was chosen to be the pilot of Unit 00.
And?  Who's the Daddy's boy who was chosen to be the pilot of Unit 01?
U-Umm...
Are you stupid?!
How irresponsible of you to not be around during such a crucial time!
What's worse, you're not even alert.
You're not even ashamed despite missing a chance to fight in an EVA unit!
It really is thanks to your father you're a pilot.
Geez, who's that girl?!
Does she have a screw loose or something?
Though, it's amazing she's already a captain despite being our age!
It's too amazing!
She must've skipped grades and graduated from university!
Excuse me.
Do I pass the barrier to the platform here to reach the Geofront Hub Terminal?
Ah, yes.
You can change trains at the station four stops ahead.
I was only away for two years, but it feels like I've been away for decades.
Thanks.  You really helped me out.
By the way, aren't you with Katsuragi?
She's an old friend of mine.
You're not the only one who knows how bad she looks when she's sleeping, Ikari Shinji-kun.
How she looks when she's sleeping, he said...
What's with that guy?
No no, it was quite the job.
The problematic Third Angel and EVA Unit 05 were dealt with, as planned.
We're insisting it was an accident.
With this, Betania Base's Marduk Project will be set back.
Everything is going according to your plan.
And, I sent the usual new information on Seele earlier-
We've seen it.
The info on the construction of Mark. 06 was very useful.
Moving on.
This is the promised item.
It's the Lost Number kept as a spare.
The guidepost to unify souls unto God.
Yes, this will open the door to Human Instrumentality.
The Key of Nebuchadnezzar.
Well then, I'll be doing my own thing for the time being.
Kaji Ryouji, Chief Inspector.
Can we trust him?
Have you lost some weight, Ricchan?
Sorry.  I've put on 1,570 grams.
I'd like to confirm that with my own eyes.
I don't mind, but this room is under surveillance.
No problem.  I've already popped in a dummy tape.
You cover your bases, as usual.
I just don't like losing.
But you already lost.
That terrifying woman is watching us.
Ryou-chan, it's been a while.
Yep, too long.
What the hell are you doing here?!
Aren't you supposed to be in Europe?
Special assignment.
I'll be here at Headquarters for a while.
The three of us can hang out together again, just like when we were in college.
I have no intention of going back to the old days!
I just have some business with Ritsuko.
I've already let the Human Resources Department know about Asuka.
Bye!
Misato's clearly jealous.
Ryou-chan, you have a chance with her.
Well, I wonder about that.
Shikinami... Asuka...
So there are actually people who happily pilot EVAs.
I'm home...
Wait, what the hell is this?
My room!
Excuse me!
That's my stuff.
Huh?
Then what about mine?  Huh?
Why are you here, Shikinami?
Are you stupid?
It means that you're being trashed.
Well, it doesn't take much to conclude who's the superior pilot here.
But...
Though, why are the rooms in Japan so small?
I can't fit even half my things in it.
Also, why do Japanese people have no sense of fear?
They can actually live in a room with no lock on it.
It's unbelievable!
That's because it is a Japanese virtue to be considerate and respectful.
Misato-san!
You're annoying.
Hurry up and get out of here with all your trash!
Shin-chan's
Room
Oh, Shin-chan will continue staying here.
Whaaat?!
What both of you lack are adequate communication skills.
As fellow pilots, you'll share in many things.
So you better get along!
Hmph!
It's an order.
Alright, together!
Thanks for the meal.
Man, beer really is best after a shower!
S-Some sort of weird creature is in the bathroom!
It's a penguin.
His name is Pen-pen-
You pervert!  Idiot!  Letch!  Unbelievable!
You're both becoming more honest with each other.  Things are going nicely.
This is why I hate guys!
Right, Pen-pen?
I'm different from them.
I'm special!
That's why, from now on...
... you can rely on yourself, Asuka.
I knew you wouldn't answer, Father.
Kaji's organizing a social studies field trip?
Yes, he also said to invite everyone.
Nothing good comes from being involved with him.
Then, I'll pass.
Nope, "make peace and listen".
Asuka, you're going too.
Is that also an order?
We're right in front of the Tabgha lunar base, but they still won't authorize a landing.
SEELE is playing dirty.
The construction method of Mark. 06 is unusual.
Being able to confirm that is enough.
But there shouldn't have been any plans for anything beyond Unit 05.
It is possible that undisclosed Dead Sea Scrolls Apocrypha exist.
SEELE intends to use them to advance their plan.
But, even SEELE must realize by now what NERV's ultimate objective is.
Even so, we have no choice but to continue forward.
Even if we are to oppose the will of God.
A person?
It can't be.
Pleased to meet you,
Father.
Wow!  This is too cool!
The preservation of extinct marine animals,
and the restoration of the
red stained sea to its original state!
This is a forbidden sanctuary that conducts experiments of divine magnitudes!
Being able to visit even a small part of it is unbelievable!
It's like the saying, "That's what friends are for"!
I gotta give ya my thanks.
Kaji-san's the one you should be thanking.
Well, things will get quite complicated from here.
Oww, hot!
Brrr, cold!
Blugh... this again?!
Noo!
No more...
Yahoo!
It's a huge aquarium!
Wow!
Are these animals that lived before the Second Impact?
Woah!  They're alive!
Awesome!  This is too awesome!
Ooh, that animal has something on its back!
I think they're called turtles.
Turtles?
Getting all excited like a bunch of kids.
How stupid.
Ayanami, I'm glad you came.
Are you feeling okay?
Yes, I was able to come today,
since I finished my assignments.
It's so cramped.
It'd be nice if they had more space to swim.
Impossible.
These little ones can't live outside this tank.
Just like me.
I'm digging in!
It's surprisingly good.
Yeah.  Nice job with the grilling and seasoning.
It's unbelievable how meat that is 90% artificial could taste so good depending on how it's prepared!
Shinji, you've been hiding your talents.
Misato-san only has instant food, so I had to learn how to cook.
Shinji-kun, men who can cook get all the girls.
Heard that?
I won't cook!
Real men don't cook!
You're being old-fashioned, how stupid.
Whatcha say?!
Ya gotta live by ya principles!
You're only making yourself look dumber.
Whatcha say?!
Whatever, just eat, eat!
Sorry, Ayanami.
You didn't like the taste?
No.  I just don't eat meat.
Why do the Japanese apologize even if they didn't do anything wrong?
And you!  Living things eat other living things to survive!
Be sure to eat every last bit of it so that it didn't die for nothing!
What is it, pet?  Wanna fight?!
Alright, comin' through...
Well then, allow me...
What?  I'm not giving you any!
You're one greedy brat!  Shoo!
Moron!
How stupid.
Then, how about some Miso soup?
It'll warm you up.
It's good.
To think that this is Mother Earth...
It's so heart-wrenching I can't even look.
However, there are people who wished for this disaster.
An world cleansed of the original sin that no man can enter.
I prefer a chaotic world that has been corrupted by man.
Chaos is in the eye of the beholder.
Everything in the world is built upon harmony and regularity.
So, it's the human heart that
throws the world into chaos?
I can't imagine that this ocean was blue before I was born.
Even the simple restoration of this environment to one that humans can live in was quite the feat.
But, this sea breeze...
... has a strange, fishy smell to it.
It's the smell of rotting marine life.
It's proof they are alive.
It's not like that mass of red water with nothing in it.
This is what the sea used to look like.
Originally, the world was wide, and filled with all kinds of life.
I wanted you guys to know that.
I'm glad I came.
Misato-san should've come with us, though.
Katsuragi wouldn't come.
It'll prompt her to remember.
Remember what?
The Second Impact.
Do you know why Katsuragi joined NERV?
Katsuragi's father was a man who lived in his research and his dreams.
She resented him for that.
In fact, I think she despised him.
So, you don't get along with your father.
Just like me.
She's just like me.
But in the end, she was saved by the very father she resented.
Being a survivor means many things.
You must accept the sacrifices of the dead, and carry on their wills.
This is all the more so if you are alone.
You're not the only one who's suffering.
The Mauna Kea Observatory detected the target three minutes ago.
Now inputting trajectory data.
Surveillance Satellite 3 has
obtained visuals of the target.
Displaying at highest magnification.
An A.T. field so powerful it can bend light...
Impressive.
Well, what is the estimated point of impact?
Obviously here, huh?
Based on Magi's re-estimate, the probability of it striking NERV Headquarters is at six nines.
The N2 aerial mines have no effect.
So, we can't change its orbit...
It's overconcentrating its A.T. field at one point.
This will add to the energy of the crash.
This means the Angel itself is a bomb.
The estimated blast size from the Eighth Angel's impact is 420,000 meters wide,
and 15,000 meters below sea level.
Tokyo-3 would be completely annihilated.
The GeoFront and even Central Dogma would be completely exposed.
And Commander Ikari?
The Angel is interfering with the radio waves in the upper atmosphere.
We are unable to contact him at present.
We'll have to deal with this ourselves.
Notify the Japanese government and each ministry.
I am issuing Order D-17 on behalf of NERV.
Begin the evacuation of all civilians within a 120 kilometer radius.
Not a problem.
Government officials have already begun the evacuation.
Evacuation of civilians in the city is complete.
Evacuation of noncombatants and Class D personnel signaled by Departmental Alarm C is complete.
The backing-up of Magi has been left to Matsushiro.
And?  What are you going to do?
The EVAs may be strong, but they can't fly in the sky.
Sniping it down is impossible from all points due to massive spatial distortions.
There's nothing we can do
against such an absurd enemy.
You're serious about this?
Yes, I am.
Can you even call this strategy a plan?
Magi predicts a failure rate of over 99 percent.
Even if we succeed, we risk losing three EVAs.
As the Chief of Engineering, I won't accept this.
The probability of success is not zero.
Steady effort trumps waiting for a miracle.
Protecting Lilith and Unit-01 should be our top priority.
I'm not waiting for a miracle.
I'll make it happen though human determination.
Colonel Katsuragi!
I am the commanding officer here.  I will make the decisions.
Furthermore, it is my duty to annihilate the Angels.
Duty?  Don't you mean grudge?
You want revenge against the Angels.
What?!
We're gonna stop it with our hands?
That's right.
You're going to directly stop the incoming Angel by maximizing your A.T. fields.
The target is distorting any information on its position,
so we cannot count on estimates based on optical observations.
So that we can respond to the situation and cover all sides,
this strategy will involve the
simultaneous launch of all three EVAs.
There's no need!
I can annihilate the Angel by myself!
That's not possible.
The predicted area of impact cannot be covered by a single EVA unit.
What is the basis for this plan?
Woman's intuition.
What a shot in the dark!
Umm... likelihood of success?
Only God would know that.
Hmph!  That's why the other EVAs would only get in the way!
I by myself am fully capable of saving mankind!
This operation does not rest on the outcomes of single combat.
Does that mean you disapprove of my ability?
That's not it.
I simply need the strength of all three of you.
In order to achieve a miracle.
All EVAs are being powered externally.
No problems with the power sources.
Connection with the New Gotenba substation complete.
Initiating insertion.
The external power supply of
Unit 00 has exceeded 105 percent.
Attaching backup power extension cables.
Squad 8, please hurry with the attachment.
Unit 01 connector link checked.  No problems.
All pilots are on standby.
Breathing rates and heart rates are at normal levels.
No problems in the final medical examinations.
Inside the EVA...
I wonder why?  I'm surprisingly calm at times like this.
Has piloting become natural to me?
I wonder why?
It feels familiar.
A scent?
The scent of my mother?
Ayanami's scent?
Currently estimating the trajectory of the target.  Input variables...
Here it comes.
All EVA units, starting positions.
Because secondary data won't be reliable, you will all be operating on your own.
Everything depends on the three of you, and the EVAs you pilot.
Target is approaching.  Distance: 20,000 meters!
Well.
Begin the operation.
Launch!
The target's A.T. field type has changed.
Its trajectory has shifted!
Estimated impact point, revised to 205.
Target is accelerating!
What's this?!  It's much faster than was estimated!
No good, I can't make it!
I'll do something about it.
Misato-san!
Form an emergency course, 605 to 675.
Roger!
Next, 1027 to 1078!
Standby!
The target has transformed!  Distance: 12,000 meters.
A.T. field, full power!
Daddy's boy!
Unit 02, the core.
I know!
Don't give me orders!
It came off?!
You just don't know when to give up!
30 seconds left.
Asuka, hurry!
I said I know!
The Commander's pet?!
Hurry...
Asuka!
Didn't I already say I know?!
One more!
Situation resolved.
Thank you, everyone.
Communication systems restored.
Incoming call from Commander Ikari.
Connect him.
I'm very sorry.
The three EVA units have been damaged under my command.
The pilots have also sustained injury.
I will assume all responsibility.
It's fine.
It is fortunate that you managed to stop the target with only this much damage.
Indeed.  Well done, Colonel Katsuragi.
Thank you, sir.
Connect me with the pilot of Unit 01.
Huh?
I heard about the situation.
Well done, Shinji.
Huh?  Yes.
Well then, Colonel Katsuragi.
I will leave the rest to you.
Yes, sir.
Recover the three EVA units.  Hurry.
Bring in Unit 01 first, to Emergency Cage 99.
I couldn't do anything... on my own.
Though it's always been normal for me to be alone...
Though being alone shouldn't bother me...
Huh, wha-
Don't turn around.
Ah... o-okay.
Let me stay here just a little, Daddy's boy.
Umm, Shikinami-san?
During today's turmoil, you called me by my first name, didn't you?
As a treat, you can call me Asuka.
I'll also call you Idiot Shinji.
Well, umm...
Asuka, why do you pilot EVA?
That's a stupid question.
Just be quiet, Idiot Shinji.
O-Okay.
I pilot EVA for myself.
What about you?
I don't really know.
Are you stupid?
That's just running away from your responsibilities.
Maybe I want to be praised by my father.
He praised me for the first time in my life today.
I believe it's the first time praise has made me happy.
I wonder if my father finally approves of me.
Maybe it's just like Misato-san said.
You...
... really are stupid.
Alright, food, food!
It's the best thing 'bout being in school!
What?  You don't have our packed lunches with you?!
I was busy doing homework this morning, so I didn't have time to make it.
So, you're telling me to spend my lunch without food?!
Like I said, I'll make it tomorrow!
What's this?  Married couple quarrelin' again?
We're not married!
Asuka, lend me your facial cleanser.
Stop using mine, Misato!
Go buy your own!
Cheapskate!
Alright, food, food!
I'm diggin' in!
It's not that great today.
It's lost some flavor from his slacking off.
Umm, Asuka-san.
Hmm?
Can I eat with you?
You're welcome to, but I'm not sharing my lunch with you.
Here.
It seems like you never eat, so...
T-Thank you.
I'm glad I decided to ask to join you-
Your name's Hikari?
You can have what's left.
Ah, I'm so full.
Thanks for the meal!
That's a pretty late lunch.
Thanks.
I heard Shinji-kun's been making your meals?
Well, you were never much of a cook.
Indeed.
Unlike you, I don't have much free time, with all this work I have to do as director.
You're hardworking, as usual.
Well, that's one of your qualities,
Katsuragi, but it's also a weakness.
I heard that you fell out with Ricchan a little while ago.
You shouldn't take things so seriously.
Unfortunately, my schedule is always full of obligations.
If you're too stressed, you won't get any guys.
That's none of your business-
"Thank you".
Words of gratitude.
Words I've never used.
I've never said them to him...
Stand!
Bow!
Take your seats!
Ayanami's absent again?
Anyway.
She seemed fine yesterday.
I wonder what's wrong?
Just like me.
"Can't live anywhere but here".
What did she mean by that?
Rei.
Let's eat.
Yes.
Commander Ikari.
What is it?
Are meals fun?
Yeah.
Do you enjoy eating with others?
Does it make you happy to have food cooked for you?
Yeah.
Commander Ikari.
Next time, would you like to have a meal with Ikari-kun and the others?
No, I don't have the ti-
Darling, please take care of Shinji.
Alright.  I will.
There are no abnormalities for all pilots in the synchronization test.
Degree of mental contamination not estimated.
Aah!
This is boring.
All we do is run tests when Angels aren't coming.
What a shame.
Isn't that a good thing?
We fight, hoping for calm days where Angels won't come.
Today's the same as yesterday.
And tomorrow will be the same as today.
An eulogy to the endless cycle of days.
If anything, it's a situation we should be thankful for.
Test is complete.
Results are good.
Good work.
The three of you can come out now.
I don't know if I should say this,
but the damage we've sustained could hinder our using them for further battles.
Why don't we just disregard the Vatican Treaty?
I'd like to.
The limit of three EVA units per country leaves us with no spare units to use.
Our current priority is to repair Unit 01.
We're barely managing this even though we're using all the spare parts we have,
so the prospect of repairing Unit 00 is grim.
The treaty involves the egos of each country.
Trying to revise it is close to impossible.
What's more, despite having lost Unit 05,
Europe and Russia are involving Asia in their various demands.
Things get more troublesome when politics is involved.
There's too much to be done before we can even get to saving mankind.
Outta the way!
Ouch...
My glasses...
Umm...
Ah, I'm sorry.
Are you alright?
Hello, Mari here.
Yes, I seem to have landed off-target.
It looks like I'm in a school of some sort.
What?
Well, you told me to enter into Japan covertly.
Can't you have your people work this out?
Just be there for my extraction later, okay?  Thanks.
You smell nice.
It's the smell of LCL.
You're interesting.
Well, don't tell anyone about this, NERV's puppy!
Huh?  Weird...
Yo!  Why don't we go on a date sometime?
But, I'm a guy.
No problem.
Gender has nothing to do with love.
Just kidding.
Here.
KAJI
The scent of the earth...
Worn out already?
You're working for your salary, you know.
Salary?
You mean the canned coffee from earlier?
Ugh, you said this was a date...
I thought you were more serious than that, Kaji-san.
For an adult, being crafty is just about right.
Are these really watermelons?
Yeah.  Aren't they cute?
It's my hobby.
To create and grow something is a great thing.
You can see all sorts of things, and learn from them.
Fun things, for instance.
Painful things too, right?
You dislike painful things?
I don't like them.
Have you found something you enjoy doing?
That's fine too.
However, only people who understand pain know how to be kind to others.
It's different from being weak.
Do you like Katsuragi?
Misato-san?  Well, uh...
I don't dislike her.
Protect Katsuragi for me.
It's not something I can do.
It's something only you can do.
Please.
Good morning.
Ayanami?!
She greeted us?
Ayanami, of all people?
Ayanami, are you okay now?
Yes, I'm fine today.
What happened to your hand?
Dr. Akagi bandaged it for me earlier.
What did she do to you?
Secret.
I'll tell you once I get a little better at speaking.
Rei's really changed.
She has.
It's unbelievable that the girl would do things for the sake of others.
To Dr. Akagi
Ayanami Rei
I wonder why?
Isn't it... love?
Come on!  That's impossible.
Idiot Shinji would probably like it a little milder, I guess...
I'm home!
Huh, Misato?
You're home early.
Yeah.  I have to go right back to Headquarters, though.
I'm just back to take a bath and change my clothes.
Oh my, what's this?
So you're cooking for Shin-chan too, Asuka?
I'm not!
It's, uh, for a girl...
Yeah, it's for Hikari!
Pfft, what's with both you and Rei
getting all romantic all of a sudden?
Hey, don't put me together with that pet!
You're right.  Rei seems to planning something grander.
What do you mean?
She seems to want to be the Cupid that will bring Shin-chan closer to Commander Ikari.
Her strategy seems to be a meal party where she does the cooking.
Its straightforwardness might actually make it work.
To the Pilot of Unit 02
Getting father and son back on good terms will require a lot of effort.
She's doing all this for Idiot Shinji?
It's meant to be a surprise for
Shin-chan, so don't let him know.
Of course I won't say anything!
Ayanami Rei
Annihilated?!
EVA Unit 04 and the Second Branch... annihilated?
This is data from T plus ten, ground zero.
That's horrible.
We were able to confirm the breaking down of an A.T. field from a satellite,
but the exact details are unknown.
So Unit 04 was the epicenter.
Are our own EVA units fine?
Unit 04 was-
Unit 04 was a testbed model with a new internals designed to tackle problems with operation time length.
Or so it seems.
The North American developmental details are not fully open, even for Dr. Akagi.
And those who do know...
EVA Unit 04.
A test unit used to obtain developmental data for the next generation of EVAs.
It's not surprising that something would happen.
However...
Was it really an accident?
Ma'am, I'll take three!
How rare of you to treat us, Touji.
I didn't think that you'd let me treat ya to a snack with us, either.
You should just be honest and say that it's because your sister's health is improving.
Shaddup!  Ya didn't havta say that much, moron!
Hey, Ikari.
Hmm?
I heard Unit 03 is coming to Japan?
Really?  I didn't know that.
There are rumors that the US is forcing Japan to perform the activation experiments.
Well, it's not information that you pilots would need.
But man, I wonder who will pilot it?
I don't know, I never heard anything.
Man, how nice it is to be a pilot!
I wonder if they'll let me become one?
Bugging me won't do anything,
Misato-san's the one who decides...
Tch, I didn't win anything.
We recently lost Evangelion Unit 05.
Now, we've also lost Unit 04.
The loss of both units will be a setback to the advancement of the project...
It is within the scope of amendment.
There won't be any problems.
The US government is imploring you to take Unit 03.
The government of your country has also been cooperative.
It's a state-of-the-art weapon.
It'll serve your fighting needs nicely.
We are in the process of eliminating the Angels even now.
I do not have enough faith in an untested unit.
If you could approve an increased budget to repair Unit 00-
The role of the prototype model will soon end.
We don't need it.
Indeed, there are other matters that should be prioritized.
The true Evangelion we desire.
Its birth and Lilith's resurrection will signify the time of our covenant.
We must perform the necessary rituals before then.
For the Human Instrumentality Project.
I understand.
It will all go according to your plan, SEELE.
The true Evangelion...
So, the purpose of the current units, including Unit 01, is to pave the way for its completion.
And is that Mark. 06?
So it's not false gods they want to create, but a true God at last?
Yes.
We must hasten the awakening of Unit 01.
EVA Unit 02's core unit separation complete.
Why is my Unit 02 being sealed?!
You know about the Vatican Treaty, don't you?
This is the condition for our receiving Unit 03.
Why don't you seal the damaged Unit 00 instead?!
The pass for Unit 02 is still being held by Europe.
There's nothing we can do about this.
Currently, its pilot has also been suspended.
Please behave yourself until we receive further notice from Europe.
Even though no one can pilot it but me?
EVA are combat weapons.
We have backups for everything.
Including the pilots.
But...
But it's the only place in the world for me...
EVA is a mirror that reflects your heart.
What was that?
You shouldn't rely on EVA.
There is happiness to be found outside of piloting them.
Don't you lecture me, you're just a pet!
I'm a prodigy, and I was chosen to pilot EVA due to my own merits!
Unlike you both, who got to pilot only because of connections!
I'm simply bonded to it.
I'm unable to bond to people without EVA.
Shut up!
You were only favored because you're a good doll who does whatever Commander Ikari wants!
I'm not a doll.
You're a doll!
Know a little more about yourself!
Hmph.  You've got some nerve for a doll.
Let me ask you just one thing.
How do you feel about that idiot?
Idiot?
I'm obviously talking about that idiot Shinji!
Ikari-kun?
Well?
I don't really know.
This is what I hate about the Japanese!
Make yourself clear already!
I don't know.
But, being with Ikari-kun makes me warm and content.
I want Ikari-kun to feel warm and content, too.
I want him to get along with Commander Ikari and feel warm and content, I think.
I understand.
You really are an ultra idiot beyond help!
That means you're in love with him!
Man, I'm looking forward to the meal party.
Though, I wonder if Ayanami's cooking will be okay.
To Ikari-kun
It'd be nice if Father could come.
The first unmanned solo Dummy System test will commence at Cage 7...
So that's the Dummy System.
Although it was only supposed to assist the pilot,
not only can it independently exert autonomous control,
but it can even exert an A.T. field while unmanned.
It's supposed to be more humane than forcing children to pilot.
There's just something about that new Dummy System thing that doesn't sit well with me!
It's something that was tightly sealed and sent directly here from Golgotha Base,
so none of us know what it really is.
I can't understand why they'd let
something so dangerous control EVA!
You're saying that the control of EVA should be left to humans?
You really trust Shinji-kun a lot.
Actually, you trust him because he's Shinji-kun.
That aside, could you give me some intel regarding SEELE, our higher-ups?
If it's that plan you're talking about, I suggest you pursue it no further.
I can't do that.
The Human Instrumentality Project...
What on Earth is NERV is doing behind the scenes?
Well...
I don't really know, either.
It's been so long since we've dined together, but all we talk about is work.
Unlike when we were college students.
We've learned many things, and carry more burdens.
And so, the both of us can no longer be selfish.
Shinji-kun and the others have been made to carry much larger burdens.
Yeah.  It's too big of a burden for kids to carry.
But, we have no choice but to rely on them.
Hello.
Yeah yeah, I know.
I'll give you an answer before the day ends.
Is that Ricchan?
Yeah.
She keeps urging me to decide on the test pilot for Unit 03.
That's because personnel selection is your responsibility.
That's true, but the test date was rescheduled due to delays with Unit 03's arrival.
And it just had to be that day, of all days...
Unit 03's activation test date...
To the Pilot of Unit 02
Isn't that also the date of that pet's meal party?
I see.  Asuka it is, then.
Yes, I'll take the last flight to Matsushiro.
Take care of things while I'm gone, Maya.
Yes, Ma'am!
Umm, Dr. Akagi?
There's something I want to say to the Second Child.
Please.
You have one new voice message.
This is the first voice message.
Okay, Rei.  You can speak now.
Thank you.
Hmph!  Is she stupid?!
It was just me wanting to pilot an EVA!
If I end up liking Unit 03, please paint it red for me.
Good morning, Aida-kun!
Absent:
Shikinami
Sup.
Huh?  Where's Touji?
His sister is being discharged from Odawara Hospital today.
I see.
Touji has a message for you.
"There's no need to worry.  My sister also appreciates it."
Ikari, isn't this just great?
Yeah.
Aren't you visiting Ayanami today?
I'm so jealous!
The director of the EVA Unit 03 manned activation test has arrived.
She is currently heading to the control room.
Checks for the Provisional Ground Cage and the Restraint Systems are complete.
Begin Umbilical Cord connection.
Connector attachment confirmed.
Switchover to the main power source complete.
Internal voltage has cleared the required threshold.
Entry plug has been fixed in entry position.
Checklist clear through 1350.  No problems.
Roger.  Begin countdown.
Begin countdown.
All ground crew are to evacuate.
Medical examinations of test pilot complete.
The pilot is currently on standby in the mobile isolation room.
Looks like I can leave the rest to Ritsuko now.
The secret line?  Asuka?
What is it, Asuka?  Calling right before the test?
I just wanted to talk to you for some reason, Misato.
I see.  I haven't properly thanked you for doing this yet, so...
Thank you.
You don't have to thank me.
It's simply the duty of the elite to protect the ignorant masses.
I mean, having a meal with everyone was never really my thing.
Pretending to have fun with the others will only wear me out.
I don't want to see others be happy.
I should just pilot EVA.
I've always liked being alone.
I never needed close friends.
There's never been anyone who sees me for who I really am.
As long as I get top scores in this test, I can deal with eating alone at NERV.
Though, recently I've been thinking that it's nice to be around others.
It's not like me to say that, though...
That's not true.
You're a kind girl, Asuka.
You're the first person I've said this to, Misato.
Somehow, I feel better now.
It feels good to talk to others.
I never knew...
This world is full of interesting things you have yet to know about.
Look forward to them.
Yeah, I will.
Thanks, Misato.
By the way, I like the red color,
but isn't this Test Plug Suit...
a little too revealing?
Start entry.
Ionizing LCL.  Pressure is at normal levels.
First excitation state is being maintained.
No problems with the plug sensor.
Diagnostic values are within error ranges.
Roger.  Move on to Phase 2.
Begin secondary connection.
I see.
I can actually smile.
Plug depth is over 100.
The risk of mental contamination has exceeded critical levels.
Why, all of a sudden?!
Plug depth has exceeded safety levels!
Restrain it!
If this continues, the pilot will no longer be human!
Abort the test!  Cut the circuits!
No good.  A high-energy reaction from within the body!
It can't be...
An Angel?!
What?
An explosion incident at Matsushiro?
What's the extent of the damage?
Unknown.
It seems that the explosion was
centered on the provisional test cage.
We've confirmed the destruction of the ground control facilities.
Send rescue teams and the Third Battalion to the rescue.
Take care of everything before the JSSDF intervenes.
Roger.
Unknown mobile object detected south-west of the blast site.
Pattern orange.
Unable to confirm whether it is an Angel.
Battle Stations One.
Ikari?
All personnel, Battle Stations One.
Place the damaged Unit 00 on standby.
Fit Unit 01 with the Dummy Plug and send it out immediately.
Tank Troop Five is positioned at the 18th defense perimeter.
Two minutes until connection of the main power extension cable is complete.
Deployment of the support strike force is complete.
Umm... how are Misato-san, Asuka, and the others?
We are currently doing our best to rescue them.
Don't worry.
But... Misato-san and the other EVAs aren't with me.
I can't do this alone!
There won't be problems with the chain of command.
Commander Ikari himself has taken charge.
Father?
We have visual confirmation near the Toomi area.
Transferring to the main monitor.
We should've known.
Transmit the deactivation signal.
Eject the entry plug by force.
It's no good!
It's not recognizing the deactivation signal or the ejection code!
A core-like invasive structure around the entry plug area has been confirmed.
Analysis pattern complete.
It's blue.
Evangelion Unit 3 is hereby abandoned.
Reclassify the target as the Ninth Angel.
Target is approaching.
Prepare for ground combat.
Anti-invasion team, begin attack.
What?  That can't be...
An Angel?  Is that an Angel?!
That's right.  That's our target.
Our target?
But isn't that an EVA?
No way...
The target is approaching.
You are to defeat it.
But, even though that's the target...
Isn't Asuka still inside?
Asuka...
Damn it...
An entry plug...
So she is in it!
The armor is being contaminated at the cervical vertebrae block!
Contamination has been confirmed to have reached Layer 6,200!
So it's a contamination-type Angel...
That's bad.
The A.T. field of Unit 01 is unstable.
Life support systems are failing.
The pilot's life will be in danger if this continues!
We can't let this happen.
Cut the synchronization down to 28 percent!
Wait.
But, Ikari, if this continues the pilot will die.
Shinji, why aren't you fighting?
But Asuka's still inside, Father!
Doesn't matter.  That thing is an Angel.
Our enemy.
But, I can't!
I can't bring myself to kill someone!
Then you'll die.
Fine!
It's better than killing Asuka!
Don't worry about him.
Cut all synchronization between the pilot and Unit 01.
Ikari?
Cut them?
That's right.
Switch control over to the Dummy System.
But, there are still many problems with the Dummy System,
and without Dr. Akagi's directions, I...
It'll be of more use than the current pilot.
Do it!
Understood.
What's this?
What are you doing, Father?!
Control system transfer complete.
All neural circuits have been
connected to the Dummy System.
Dummy System has at most
208 seconds of active time remaining.
Doesn't matter.
Release the system.  Commence the attack.
Let's stay friends
いつまでも絶えることなく
Forever and ever
友達でいよう
We'll dream of tomorrow
明日の日は夢見て
Is this the power of the Dummy System?
Dummy system nominal.
And walk the road of hope
希望の道を
Control limiters are being removed.
We will live freely
空を飛ぶ 鳥のように
Like a bird flying in the sky
自由に生きる
Today, we say goodbye
今日の日はさようなら
Until the day we meet again
また会う日まで
Today, we say goodbye
今日の日はさようなら
Until the day we meet again
また会う日まで
What is this, Father...
What is this?  What are you doing?!
Damn it, stop, stop!
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop...
Let's treasure the joy
信じあう喜びを
Of believing in each other
大切にしよう
What's that sound?
Today, we say goodbye
今日の日はさようなら
No, stop!
STOP!
Until the day we meet again
また会う日まで
I'm alive?
Kaji?
That's good, Katsuragi.
How's Ritsuko?
Don't worry.
Her injuries aren't as bad as yours.
I see.
What about Asuka?  EVA Unit 03?
It's been dealt with as an Angel.
By Unit 01.
The linking circuits of Unit 01 have been cut.
And the ejection signal?
It's locked from inside the plug.
He's locked himself in.
That's enough, Shinji-kun!
Think about what you're doing!
Don't make me any angrier with those words.
There are still 285 seconds remaining on Unit 01.
With this, I can destroy half of Headquarters.
In his current state, chances are he'll do it.
Shinji-kun, please listen!
If it weren't for Commander Ikari's decision,
you could've been killed!
That has nothing to do with it.
But that's the truth!
Didn't I just say that it has nothing to do with it?!
My father, he tried to murder Asuka!
With my own hands!
Why?  Why?!
Why, damn it?!
You don't understand anything, Father!
I was a fool to believe in you!
You should just go and lose someone important to you too, Father!
Then you'll understand!
Increase the concentration of the LCL to the limit.
I have no time to be dealing with a brat's tantrums.
I still have direct control-
Damn it...
Damn it... damn it...
Ikari-kun.
You're always listening to that, aren't you?
Yeah.
It's something my father used back in the day.
It's just like the glasses you have, Ayanami.
Though, he decided he didn't need it anymore, and left it behind.
Just like me.
He left it behind at my teacher's place, so I took it.
When I close off my ears, I close off my heart, too.
Then, I don't have to face this world I hate.
World you hate?
Yeah.
A world where the father I hate lives.
A world with frightening Angels and EVAs.
A world that makes you do terrible things.
A world where my father no longer needs me now that he has the Dummy Plug.
A world where my friends and I are hurt.
Though there are some good things, in the end they are all destroyed.
It's a world I hate.
I'm rejecting it.
I thought that my father would protect me from this world I hate if I had this with me.
But I was just deluding myself.
Didn't you try to understand your father, Ikari-kun?
I tried to.
But you didn't do anything.
I did try to!
It's Father's fault!
Wasn't it him who abandoned me?!
And just like this, you're going to run away from things you hate again.
And what's wrong with that?
What's wrong with running away from things you hate?!
Here again.
No more...
Vehicles recovering the remnants of Unit 03 should each have...
Although all traces of cellular
contamination have disappeared,
we cannot rule out the possibility of mental contamination from the Angel.
Our only option is to keep her quarantined.
They're not going to kill her, are they?
She's a precious specimen.
It won't happen.
Out you come, Ikari Shinji-kun.
Commander Ikari will see you now.
Insubordination.
Private appropriation of an EVA.
Blatant extortion.
These are all criminal offenses.
Do you have anything to say for yourself?
Yes.  I don't want to pilot EVA ever again.
I see.
Then get out of here.
You're running away again?
You need to sacrifice everything and use
your own strength in order to fulfill your desires.
It's not something others can do for you.
Shinji.  Grow up.
I don't know what it is to be an adult.
It's me.  Erase all records of the Third Child.
From now on, Unit 01 will be
piloted by the Dummy System.
There will be no need for a backup.
Rei didn't stop Shinji-kun from leaving.
She's changed quite a bit recently, so I was expecting her to.
We really can't gauge the relationship between the two of them.
But with this, we only have one pilot again.
I guess we're back to where we started.
I think you already know this,
but even though your records have been erased, you will continue to be monitored,
and your activities will be severely restricted.
You forgot this.
Suzuhara-kun and Aida-kun left you several voice messages.
They're worried about you.
I don't need it.
I left it behind on purpose.
You don't want to know about Rei and Asuka?
To be honest, maybe I don't care about things like the fate of humanity and the world.
I may hold the position I have now,
but initially it was only because I wanted to be at least a little closer to my deceased father
that I joined NERV.
It's the same reason you piloted EVA because Commander Ikari needed you to.
That's why piled my own feelings and hopes onto you.
I knew that they would burden you.
I know that you are disappointed with
what happened when you piloted EVA.
But even so, I still-
Rei also invited Commander Ikari that day.
She wanted you and your father to get along.
She wanted you both to smile together.
I will never...
... smile with anyone again.
Next stop is Kamigoura, Kamigoura.
Please exit on the left.
The Japanese government has now declared a state of emergency.
In accordance with emergency regulations, this train will stop at the nearest evacuation station.
Please head to the designated platform
quickly after alighting and board the incline.
An Angel.
Brr, it's freezing.
It's the new suit alright.
My boobs fit perfectly, it feels... great!
The time has come.
All personnel, Battle Stations One.
Prepare for surface-to-air interception.
The target?
It's currently advancing forward.
It broke through the Old Odawara defense perimeter.
That blast must've been huge for the shockwaves to reach even here.
District 4 suffered a direct hit.
Losses unknown.
All surface armor systems have been melted!
It broke through all 24 layers of special armor in one hit...
So, the Tenth Angel is the strongest rejection-type.
Its destructive power is unbelievable.
Launch an all-out attack!
Make use of all anti-invasion facilities within the fortified city!
It doesn't matter by how much, slow it down!
EVA Unit 02?!
Who's piloting it?
Unknown.
It was not us who issued the launch order.
Target intact.
The second wave of N2 mines had no effect.
That's fine.  The evacuation of citizens is top priority!
The third wave of N2 mines has been authorized!  Get them ready!
The EVAs won't make it in time to intercept it on the surface.
Request the cooperation of Europe.
Deploy Unit 02 to the Geofront!
What about Unit 00?
The left arm is undergoing emergency treatment.
It should be barely usable!
Once that's done, send it in to assist Unit 02.
Fighting without backup is too risky.
Roger.
What about Unit 01?
It's currently being prepared for
activation with the Dummy System.
Make it quick!
Wasn't that from the city area?
Hey, what's going on?
It's fine, the Geofront shelter is right ahead.
My phone's not working.
It's the safest place out there.
The target is infiltrating Geofront!
EVA Unit 02 is about to engage it!
How is the communication with Unit 02?
The two-way link has been cut, there's nothing we can do...
I see.
So she wants to fight alone.
It smells good...
Although this EVA smells of
someone else, it's not a bad smell.
The 5th defense perimeter will be breached soon.
I better take care of this quickly, or Headquarters will go poof!
Its A.T. field is too strong.
No progress will be made at this rate!
Let's try this.
If it's at point-blank...
Owww...
Oh, no!
Bastard, not bad at all!
Dummy System has been connected.
Start contact.
Roger!
What's wrong?
The core unit is rejecting the dummy!
It's no good!  EVA Unit 01 won't activate!
It's not accepting the dummy?
Fuyutsuki.
Take care of things for me for a bit.
I can't win at this rate.
Alright, let's try this.
I'll show you the power of an EVA that has abandoned its humanity.
Invert mode.
Secret code: "The Beast"!
Hang in there, EVA Unit 02.
I'll endure it with you!
EVA actually has functions like that?
The limiters are being removed!
All readings are beyond standards!
Unable to monitor the plug interior!
But...
It's likely that the plug depth has reached negative values.
This means the pilot was fine with entering the contamination zone.
We can't!
It's too dangerous!
Nothing... ventured...
Nothing...
... gained!
Again!
The bestialized second configuration of EVA.
It still couldn't win even after it abandoned its humanity to become combat-specialized.
There's nothing more we can do.
Unit 00?!
Without a rifle?
No way...
Rei, stop!
Rei!
A.T. field, full power!
Even if...
Even if Ikari-kun won't pilot EVA, I'll make it alright!
So please...
That A.T. field cannot be broken by a single EVA unit!
Unit 02, this is your final task!
One... more!
Run, pilot of Unit 02!
Thank you.
Where's Unit 00?
This shelter has been designated as a hazardous zone.
Please evacuate to a safety zone as soon as possible.
I repeat-
Owww...
I was pretty close to dying, meow...
Huh?  What are you doing here?
I guess this explains why we were short of one unit.
I...
I've already decided not to pilot.
So there's actually someone out there who wracks his brains about whether or not to pilot EVA.
Well then, you should hurry up and run.
Here, I'll help you.
I'm not going to pilot.
I'm not going to pilot...
You know, you won't have any fun if you keep fretting like that.
No way, the Angel consumed the EVA...
That's impossible!
This is strange, the target's identification signal is turning into Unit 00's!
It got us!
Now, Dogma won't self-destruct even if that thing gets inside!
It'll be able to reach Lilith with no effort!
It's fusing with Unit 00.
It even absorbed the pilot.
You'll die too, if you don't hurry up and run!
Ah, he left...
Headquarters' ground facilities have been annihilated!
Third foundation has suffered a direct hit!
Final armor plating has been melted!
Oh, no!
The main shaft is completely exposed!
Unit 01 isn't ready yet?
Unable to fix plug to entry position!
It's rejecting the signal to connect the Dummy System!
It's no good, resetting it doesn't help!
Keep trying.
Start again from 308.
List 308...
Why?
Why are you refusing me, Yui?
Let me pilot it!
Please...
... let me pilot Unit 01!
What are you doing here?
Father!
I am the pilot of Evangelion Unit 01...
Ikari Shinji!
The target has descended past seventh layer of Terminal Dogma!
It's coming here.
All noncombatants, evacuate!
All noncombatants are to evacuate immediately!
I repeat, all noncombatants are to evacuate-
EVA Unit 01?!
Shinji-kun!
Misato-san!
Release the locks!
Out of energy?
Unit 01 has reached the end of its active time limit!
The backup reserves are depleted, too!
Shinji-kun...
Shinji-kun!
Give Ayanami...
... back to me!
It's moving?
But it should be at the end of its active time limit...
It's going berserk?
I don't know...
What on Earth is happening with Unit 01?
Such power in an EVA...
Has Unit 01 transcended human limits?
Plug depth is over 180!
Reaching critical levels!
Stop, Shinji-kun!
You won't be able to become human again!
What happens to me doesn't matter.
What happens to the world doesn't matter.
But, Ayanami...
At least Ayanami...
I'll definitely save her!
Go for it, Shinji-kun!
Misato?
This isn't for someone else!
It's for the sake of your own wishes!
Ayanami, where are you?!
It's too late.
I'm no longer able to live anywhere else but here.
Ayanami!
It's fine, Ikari-kun.
Even if I disappear, I'll be replaced.
I'll be replaced...
You're wrong!
There's no other Ayanami but you!
That's why I'll save you now!
If you could grant my wish
今 私の願いごとが叶うならば
Oh, no...
Its physical limiters are disappearing!
Analysis impossible!
Breaking free of the human limits that restricted it,
the EVA now returns to its original form.
It has dissolved the curse humans have placed on it,
and has exceeded humans to transform into a near-Godlike existence.
I'd wish for wings
翼がほしい
Inside the huge waves of complementarity,
it spins Heaven, Earth, and all creation together,
Please place white wings on my back
この背中に鳥のように
transforming itself into a condensed energy form.
It's doing that to grant the wish of one human being.
Just for that.
Just like a bird's
白い翼つけてください
I want to spread my wings
この大空に翼を広げ
And fly off into the wide sky
飛んで行きたいよ
Ayanami!
Towards the sky, free and without sorrow
悲しみのない自由な空へ
I will beat my wings and fly
翼はためかせ 行きたい
Ayanami!
I still see even now
子どものとき夢見たこと
Ayanami!  Give me your hand!
Come!
The dream I saw as a child
今も同じ夢に見ている
I want to spread my wings
この大空に翼を広げ
And fly off into the wide sky
飛んで行きたいよ
Towards the sky, free and without sorrow
悲しみのない自由な空へ
Unit 01 was triggered before the rest of the units were ready...
I will beat my wings
翼はためかせ
Commander Ikari, SEELE won't be quiet about this.
I want to spread my wings
この大空に翼をひろげ
As we thought, the two of them
were enough to awaken Unit 01.
Yeah.
Just a little more until our project is complete.
And fly off into the wide sky
飛んで行きたいよ
Towards the sky, free and without sorrow
悲しみのない自由な空へ
Ayanami, about my father...
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
I will beat my wings
翼はためかせ
I couldn't do anything.
It's fine.
I'm fine with this.
I want to spread my wings
この大空に翼を広げ
And fly off into the wide sky
飛んで行きたいよ
I see.
He's quite the convenient fellow.
Towards the sky, free and without sorrow
悲しみのない自由な空へ
I wonder if it's because he smelled different?
I will beat my wings and fly
翼はためかせ 行きたい
I want to spread my wings
この大空に翼を広げ
And fly off into the wide sky
飛んで行きたいよ
Towards the sky, free and without sorrow
悲しみのない自由な空へ
I will beat my wings and fly
翼はためかせ 行きたい
This is the birth of a new life that
transcends the logos of this world.
The cost of it is the elimination of older life.
Wings.
Just like 15 years ago.
Yes.
It's the continuation of the Second Impact.
The Third Impact has begun.
The world is about to end.
A
UTW-THORA Staff:
Translator:
Raze
Timer:
Sindalf
Editor:
Raze
Typesetter:
adenozin
It's only love
If I can be granted just one wish
moshimo negai hitotsu dake kanau nara
もしも願い一つだけ叶うなら
kimi no soba de nemurasete donna basho demo ii yo
Let me sleep by your side, wherever that may be
君の側で眠らせて　どんな場所でもいいよ
Beautiful world
mayowazu kimi dake wo mitsumete iru
Unwavering, my eyes are only on you
迷わず君だけを見つめている
Beautiful boy
jibun no utsukushisa mada shiranai no
You still don't know how beautiful you are
自分の美しさ　まだ知らないの
It's only love
netemo sametemo shounen manga
Whether sleeping or awake
寝ても覚めても少年マンガ
yume mite baka jibun ga suki janai no
All you dream of is teenage comics, don't you like yourself?
夢見てばっか　自分が好きじゃないの
nani ga hoshii ka wakaranakute
You don't know what you want, but you can't stop wanting
何が欲しいか分からなくて
tada hoshigatte nurui namida ga hoho wo tsutau
Warm tears roll down your cheeks
ただ欲しがって　ぬるい涙が頬を伝う
iitai koto nanka nai
I have nothing I want to tell you
言いたいことなんか無い
tada mouichido aitai
I just want to meet you once more
ただもう一度会いたい
iitai koto ienai
I can't say what I want to say
言いたいこと言えない
konjou nashi kamo shirenai
Maybe I'm just a coward
根性無しかもしれない
sorede ii kedo
But that's all right too
それでいいけど
moshimo negai hitotsu dake kanau nara
If I can be granted just one wish
もしも願い一つだけ叶うなら
kimi no soba de nemurasete donna basho demo ii yo
Let me sleep by your side, wherever that may be
君の側で眠らせて　どんな場所でもいいよ
Beautiful world
mayowazu kimi dake wo mitsumeteiru
Unwavering, my eyes are only on you
迷わず君だけを見つめている
Beautiful boy
jibun no utsukushisa mada shiranai no
You still don't know how beautiful you are
自分の美しさ　まだ知らないの
It's only love
donna koto demo yatte mite
No matter what it is, give everything a try
どんなことでもやってみて
son wo shitatte sukoshi keikenchi agaru
Even if you lose out, it's a valuable experience
損をしたって　少し経験値上がる
shinbun nanka iranai
I don't need newspapers
新聞なんかいらない
kanjin na koto ga nottenai
What's important to me isn't printed there
肝心なことが載ってない
saikin choushi dou dai?
How have you been lately?
最近調子どうだい?
genki ni shiteru nara
As long as you are well
元気にしてるなら
betsu ni ii kedo
I'll be fine
別にいいけど
boku no sekai kieru made aenu nara
If I can't meet you before my world ends
僕の世界消えるまで会えぬなら
kimi no soba de nemurasete donna basho demo kekkou
Let me sleep by your side, wherever that may be
君の側で眠らせて　どんな場所でも結構
Beautiful world
hakanaku sugiteyuku hibi no naka de
As these fleeting days pass by
儚く過ぎて行く日々の中で
Beautiful boy
kibun no mura wa shikatanai ne
I can't help it but feel uneasy
気分のムラは仕方ないね
moshimo negai hitotsu dake kanau nara
If I can be granted just one wish
もしも願い一つだけ叶うなら
kimi no soba de nemurasete
Let me sleep by your side
君の側で眠らせて
Beautiful world
Beautiful boy
It's only love
What on Earth was that?!
Now, the Promised time has come, Ikari Shinji-kun.
This time, I'll definitely...
... make you happy.
TO BE CONTINUED
PREVIEW
EVA Unit 01 is immobilized with Rei and Shinji still trapped inside.
The fortified city in ruins.
The NERV personnel imprisoned.
EVA Unit 06 descends at Dogma.
The quickening EVA Unit 08 and its pilot.
The children chosen by fate finally assemble.
How will this tale of people who wish to survive play out?
Next, on Evangelion New Theatrical Version: Q!
There'll also be plenty of fanservice!